Inventory of the Elizabeth S. Selden papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Elizabeth S. Selden papers
1946-1949
62012
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes 0.8 linear feet
Clippings, writings, and notes, relating to conditions in Germany following World War II, the Berlin blockade, reparations, displaced persons, and denazification.
Selden, Elizabeth S., 1888-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1962.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Staff member, Education Branch, United States Military Government in Germany, 1946-1948.
Scope and Content of Collection
Newspaper clippings, writings, and notes, relating to conditions in Germany following World War II, the Berlin blockade, education, reparations, displaced persons, and denazification.
Newspaper clippings were arranged by Elizabeth Selden alphabetically by category, and then by year. This arrangment has been maintained.
This collection also contains a series of essays written by Berlin school children describing their lives in post World War II Berlin, documenting food and power shortages.
Berlin (Germany)--Description and travel.; Berlin (Germany)--History--1945-1990.; Berlin (Germany)--History--Blockade, 1948-1949.; Denazification.; Germany--History--1945-1955.; Military government.; Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; World War, 1939-1945--Reparations.
- Newspaper Clippings, 1947-1949
  - Coal-Food, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Foreign Policy-Nazi, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - News-Russian Zone, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Scientists-Zion, 1947 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Occupation-Railroads, 1948 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Refugees-Stateless, 1948 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Sweden-Zion, 1948 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Austria, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Life in Berlin, Blockade, Education, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 2: 2, Box-folder 2: 3)
- Speeches and Essays, 1947 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Children's Testimonies about Life in Berlin, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 2: 5)